[{"question": "In file with extension ___ I'm not expecting to find configuration data.", "answer": ".pid", "answers": [".cfg", ".pid", ".ini", ".conf"]}, {"question": "In which directory can configuration files be found?", "answer": "/etc", "answers": ["/home", "/var", "/tmp", "/etc"]}, {"question": "Which protocol is used by DHCP to send data?", "answer": "UDP", "answers": ["HTTP", "MMA", "TCP", "UDP"]}, {"question": "To install Active Directory service in Windows Serwver, we need to configure ...", "answer": "DNS", "answers": ["DNS", "FTP", "DHCP", "WWW"]}, {"question": "I want to install a program which is not available in base repository. How should I do it?", "answer": "All of the above.", "answers": ["Add third party repository.", "Install from source.", "Install precompiled version (ex. .deb)", "All of the above."]}, {"question": "Choose linux command to change ownership rules of a files and directories.", "answer": "chown", "answers": ["ls", "chown", "change-owner", "chmod"]}, {"question": "Which sequence will set variable DB_ADDRESS available during script execution?", "answer": "DB_ADDRESS=value; python setup.py", "answers": ["DB_ADDRESS=value; python setup.py", "\u00c5\u00bcadna z powy\u00c5\u00bcszych", "export DB_ADDRESS=value; python setup.py"]}, {"question": "Select openSSH tools.", "answer": "ssh, ssh-copy-id, ssh-agent, ssh-keygen", "answers": ["None below.", "ssh, ssh-copy-id, ssh-agent, ssh-keygen", "ssh, ssh-share-id, ssh-keyagent", "eval, ssh, ssh-add, ssh-copy-id"]}, {"question": "Choose set of programs used for automation of system configuration.", "answer": "chef, puppet, ansible", "answers": ["chef, puppet, ansible", " bash, python, htop", "inux, apache, mysql, php (LAMP)", "openssh, telnet, RDP, VNC"]}, {"question": "Choose remote access protocols.", "answer": "SSH, telnet, RDP", "answers": ["http, ftp, dns", " IP, IPX, UDP", "SSH, telnet, RDP", "http, SSH, SMTP"]}, {"question": "Public key generated for private RSA key...", "answer": "will be placed in authorized_keys.", "answers": ["is avaliable ony in UNIX systems.", "requires a user's signature.", "will be placed in authorized_keys.", "none of the above."]}, {"question": "Choose set of commands used for changing service state.", "answer": "start, status, restart, reload", "answers": ["start, stop, restart", "load, unload, reload", "start, permission, status", "reload, up, down"]}, {"question": "'$chmod 337 file_name' - this command will set following rules for 'file_name'...", "answer": "-wx-wxrwx", "answers": ["-wx-wxrwx", "-w-wxrwx", "-wx-wx-rwx", "wxwxrwx"]}, {"question": "LDAP is...", "answer": "Lightweight Directory Access Protocol", "answers": ["LDAP Data Interchange Format", "Lightweight Directory Access Protocol", "LDAP Database Interchange Format", "LDAP Data File"]}, {"question": "RDS - Remote Desktop Services uses RDP protocol which is a used in ___ system family.", "answer": "Windows", "answers": ["Windows", "Linux", "MacOS", "All of the above."]}, {"question": "SSH uses port ...", "answer": "22", "answers": ["8080", "21", "22", "20"]}, {"question": "You want optimize time of system script execution. Which command can help you with estimation of how much system time does it take?", "answer": "strace", "answers": ["uptime", "ps aux", "top", "strace"]}, {"question": "Choose set of packet managment tools for OS.", "answer": "apt, yum, brew", "answers": ["nginx, apache, httpd", "pip, maven, npm", "git, svn, hg", "apt, yum, brew"]}, {"question": "NSLOOKUP in MS Windows will among others display...", "answer": "IP address of DNS server.", "answers": ["IP address of DNS server.", "IP address of DHCP server.", "IP address of host.", "IP address of default gate."]}, {"question": "NSLOOKUP in MS Windows will among others display...", "answer": "IP address of DNS server.", "answers": ["IP address of DNS server.", "IP address of DHCP server.", "IP address of host.", "IP address of default gate."]}, {"question": "Processes own info can be found in...", "answer": "/proc/self", "answers": ["/etc/proc/me", "/proc/self", "/procs/self", "proc/me"]}, {"question": "httpd service doesn't work on restart. Where should I find reasons?", "answer": "/var/log/httpd/error.log", "answers": ["/~", "/etc/passwd", "/etc/errors", "/var/log/httpd/error.log"]}, {"question": "Passive heath check of service availability...", "answer": "/var/log/httpd/error.log", "answers": ["/~", "/etc/passwd", "/etc/errors", "/var/log/httpd/error.log"]}, {"question": "When '@ WARNING: UNPROTECTED PRIVATE KEY FILE' will be called?", "answer": "When public key have too wide access rights.", "answers": ["When remote machine can't decode the key?", "When user doesn't have sudo rights.", "When private key have too wide access rights.", "When public key have too narrow access rights."]}, {"question": "What can Load Balancer do?", "answer": "Reduce risk of service failure if one machine is broken.", "answers": ["Reduce risk of service failure if one machine is broken.", "Reduce risk of failure of the machine it is installed on.", "Speed up single instance of application.", "All above."]}, {"question": "What Active Direcory does NOT allow to do?", "answer": "Create local users.", "answers": ["Create domain users.", "Create local users.", "Creation of global groups.", "Managing access to unshared resources."]}, {"question": "das", "answer": "asd", "answers": [[], "asd"]}, {"question": "dasd", "answer": "dasd", "answers": ["dasd", "adsas"]}, {"question": "a", "answer": "s", "answers": ["s", "s", "s"]}, {"question": "d", "answer": "d", "answers": ["d", "d"]}, {"question": "v", "answer": "v", "answers": ["v", "v"]}, {"question": "a", "answer": "a", "answers": ["a", "a"]}]